Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Highest Degree: Other [Computer Science]

Notice Period: 1 Month

Vishesh Agarwal (1) Featured

Software Development Engineer seeking roles in Application Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Batch, Microservices, REST Api, Jenkins



Current Designation: Software Development Engineer - Java

Current Company: Verifone

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Bengaluru / Bangalore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Development Engineer, Software Developer, Application Development, Application

Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, Spring

Boot, Maven, Spring Batch, Microservices, REST Api, Jenkins

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Working as Software Development Engineer in VeriFone India Technology Pvt. Ltd. (1 year) and previously worked as a Software Engineer in SoftServ Solutions Private Limited (8 Months), as Software Engineer in EnbraunTechnologies (1 yr). Have carried out various kinds of activities covering all stages of SDLC and worked in Agile environment too. Has ability to do multitasking and possess leadership qualities.

Interested in doing challenging works and keen in learning new things (Passion can be seen in learning or discovering out new concepts/things). This can be easily visualized by looking out the projects undertaken so far.

Work Experience

Verifone as Software Development Engineer -Java Nov 2019 to Till Date

I am working as software development engineer in verifone. I have worked on various pim and settlement projects, i am currently working on technologies like spring boot, spring batch, jenkins, jira, maven, core java, agile, postman, intellij.

Verifone India Technology Pvt. Ltd. as Software Development Engineer - Java Nov 2019 to Nov 2019

Job Profile: Working as software developer for Verifone on payment gateways. I am involved in both e-commerce and card present part. Worked on various settlement projects i.e French settlement, Elavon settlement. Also worked on various pim project like Evry pim, Elavon pim. Worked on end to end mapping and maintaining confluence pages. Performed application testing and debugging to make efficient error free software.

Skill Set: Java, Confluence, GIT, JIRA, Maven, GitBash, Intellij Idea, Postman, Jira, Jenkins, BitBucket.

Softserv Solutions Private Limited as Software Engineer Jan 2019 to Nov 2019

Job Profile: Worked as a software developer in softserv solutions private limited. Worked on AwareIM tool for rapid application development. Worked on SQL and git. Also worked on REST api and various CRUD operations. Worked on application debugging and bug fixing.

Skill Set: Java, GIT, Confluence, SQL, Eclipse, Workbench.

Enbraun Technologies as Software Engineer

Feb 2018 to Jan 2019

Job Profile: Worked as a software engineer in enbraun technologies. Worked on java and git also worked on jira for maintaining tickets. Worked on REST api and CRUD operations. Also performed application debugging. Skill Set: Java, GIT, GitBash, Jira, Postman, Eclipse

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from government engineering college ajmer in 2017

PG: Other (Computer Science) in 0

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

CertificateOfCompletion_Introducing Maven

Core Java

CertificateOfCompletion_Introduction to Data Structures & Algorithms in Java

CertificateOfCompletion_Learning Jenkins

CertificateOfCompletion_Learning Spring with Spring Boot

CertificateOfCompletion_Mastering Microservices with Java

CertificateOfCompletion_Planning and Releasing Software with JIRA

CertificateOfCompletion_Spring_Spring Batch

CertificateOfCompletion_SQL Essential Training

Master_Restful_API_Using_Spring_Boot

Cracking the Product Interview: Pattern Recognition & Problem-Solving in DS & Algo"

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
spring boot		
MAVEN		
SPRING BATCH		
MicroServices		
REST API		
Jenkins		
JIRA, Bitbucket		
GIT		
Junit Tests, Sonar Qube		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Elavon Settlement

Client: ELAVON

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked on French settlement which is developed using java and spring batch. in this we read the transaction from the database process it and write them into the file with proper status code. Also worked on the end to end mapping on the confluence.

Project Title: Elavon pim

Client: ELAVON

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2020 - Till Date

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked on Elavon pim which was developed using spring boot and java. In this we get request from the terminal then we process that transaction and then save it into the database. Also worked on the mapping parton confluence for this project

Project Title: Evry PIM Client: EVRY India

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Apr 2020 - Jul 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked on Evry pim which was developed using spring boot and java. In this we get request from the terminal then we process that transaction and then save it into the database. Also worked on the mapping parton confluence for this project

Project Title: French Settlement

Client: omnichannel

Duration: Jan 2020 - Mar 2020 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked on French settlement which is developed using java and spring batch. in this we read the transaction from the database process it and write them into the file with proper status code. Also worked on the end to end mapping on the confluence

Project Title: iWarrenty Client: Extended warrenty

Duration: Mar 2019 - Oct 2019 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Worked on iwarrenty which was a helthcare project developed using awareim, java and sgl.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time